Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're going to buy some food at a store for basically
我是Catherine，今天我们要去商店买些食物，主要是
bread, right Marco?
面包，对吧Marco？
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going to a bakery.
今天我们要去一家面包店。
So, this is basically a shop where they sell bread and different types of bread actually.
所以，这基本上是一家卖面包的店，而且实际上有不同种类的面包。
That's right.
没错。
So, we're going to learn all about these different kinds of bread.
那么，我们将学习这些不同种类的面包。
Let's take a listen to our dialogue.
让我们来听听我们的对话。
Welcome to Al's Bakery.
欢迎来到Al's面包店。
What can I get you?
您想要点什么？
Hi, let me get a dozen croissants, four blueberry muffins and a loaf of sourdough bread.
嗨，给我来一打牛角包、四个蓝莓松饼和一条酸面包。
Sure.
好的。
Would you like to have the loaf sliced?
您需要把面包切片吗？
No, that's okay.
不用了，这样就好。
Do you have any whole wheat bread?
你们有全麦面包吗？
Oh, we're out at the moment.
哦，现在卖完了。
May I suggest some rye bread?
我可以推荐一些黑麦面包吗？
Sure, that sounds good.
好的，听起来不错。
Do you have any cakes?
你们有蛋糕吗？
We have various birthday cakes and also some ice cream cakes.
我们有各种生日蛋糕，还有一些冰淇淋蛋糕。
I'll just take a cheesecake.
我就拿一个芝士蛋糕吧。
Will that be all?
就这些吗？
Yes.
是的。
Your total is $43.20.
总共是43.20美元。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So, now let's take a look at some vocab on Language Takeaway.
那么，现在让我们看看“语言小贴士”里的一些词汇。
Language Takeaway.
语言小贴士。
In Language Takeaway today we have many different kinds of bread.
今天的“语言小贴士”里有很多不同种类的面包。
The first kind actually comes to English from the French language.
第一种其实是从法语进入英语的。
We have croissants.
我们有牛角包。
That's right, croissants.
没错，牛角包。
Now, as you say, this is a type of bread that comes from France, I guess.
就像你说的，这大概是一种来自法国的面包。
That's right.
没错。
It's really delicious.
它真的很好吃。
It's buttery and flaky and it's in the shape of a crescent.
它黄油味浓郁、酥脆，而且形状像月牙。
So, it's like a curve, like a C. It kind of looks like also horns because it's got two
所以它像一条曲线，像字母C。它看起来也有点像角，因为它有两个
little... It's got a horn on each side.
小小的……每边都有一个角。
It does.
确实如此。
Many people like to eat this for breakfast in France, but you can find it everywhere
在法国，很多人喜欢早餐吃这个，但你到处都能找到它，
in America at cafes and bakeries.
在美国的咖啡馆和面包店里也有。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So, those are croissants.
那么，这些就是牛角面包。
Now we're also buying blueberry muffins.
现在我们还要买蓝莓马芬。
Okay, muffins are a delicious baked good.
好的，马芬是一种美味的烘焙食品。
Blueberry muffins are the flavor, so we can also have strawberry or orange.
蓝莓马芬是口味之一，所以我们也可以有草莓或橙子味的。
But in this case a muffin is kind of like a sweet baked good.
但在这里，马芬是一种类似甜烘焙食品的东西。
It's round.
它是圆形的。
So, it's kind of like a cake, like a little cake.
所以，它有点像蛋糕，像一个小蛋糕。
It is like a little cake.
它就像一个小蛋糕。
The top is bigger than the bottom.
顶部比底部大。
So, the bottom you have some paper to hold on to and the top is round and maybe a little
所以，底部有一些纸可以拿着，顶部是圆的，可能有点
bit hard.
硬。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So, those are muffins.
那么，这些就是马芬。
We'll post pictures of these on the site so you can see what they look like.
我们会在网站上贴出这些图片，这样你们就能看到它们长什么样了。
But moving on now, we have a type of bread.
但现在我们继续，有一种面包。
This is a sourdough bread.
这是酸面包。
All right.
好的。
So, there are many, many, many different kinds of breads, but sourdough is very unique because
所以，面包有很多很多很多不同的种类，但酸面包非常独特，因为
the flavor is a little bit sour.
它的味道有点酸。
It's strong.
味道很浓。
So, dough is the substance or what you use to make bread, right, or before bread is baked.
那么，面团就是用来做面包的物质，或者说在面包烤制前的原料，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So, before you make bread, it's kind of like a liquid.
所以，在做面包之前，它有点像液体。
You have some milk or water that you mix with flour, so you have to hold it in a bowl or
你会加一些牛奶或水，和面粉混合，所以得用碗或
a cup.
杯子装着。
And after you bake it, it becomes hard.
烤完之后，它就变硬了。
So, dough is when it's soft and like a liquid.
所以，面团就是柔软、像液体时的状态。
Right.
对。
You've seen it when they're making bread.
你见过他们做面包的样子。
They have this, it looks like a paste sometimes and then it becomes hard or when they're making
他们会有这个，有时候看起来像糊状，然后变硬，或者做
pizzas that's called dough.
披萨时，那也叫面团。
And sour, obviously, because it has that flavor that you said, a very strong sour flavor.
而“酸”显然是因为它有你说的那种味道，一种很强烈的酸味。
That's right.
没错。
And a different kind of bread that we might find is whole wheat bread.
另一种我们可能找到的面包是全麦面包。
Okay.
好的。
Now, this is like the healthy choice.
这个就像是健康的选择。
Yes, it's normally the healthy choice.
是的，这通常是健康的选择。
That's because the flour that we put in the dough is whole wheat flour.
那是因为我们放进面团里的面粉是全麦面粉。
It's a little bit healthier.
它稍微健康一点。
It's actually a little bit darker than white flour, so it'll be brown.
它实际上比白面粉颜色深一些，所以会是棕色的。
So, yeah, it's basically the brown bread.
所以，是的，它基本上就是棕色面包。
I think if you've noticed when you go to the store and you can get bread, you'll find one
我想如果你注意到，去商店买面包时，你会发现一种
that looks white on the inside and this one actually looks brown on the inside.
里面是白色的，而这种里面实际上是棕色的。
That's right.
没错。
And an even more brown colored bread, maybe even black, is rye bread.
还有一种颜色更深的棕色面包，甚至可能是黑色的，那就是黑麦面包。
So, what is rye?
那么，什么是黑麦？
Rye is another kind of grain and when you bake this rye bread, it has a very strong
黑麦是另一种谷物，当你烤这种黑麦面包时，它有一种很浓的
flavor and it's very, very dark, almost black.
味道，而且颜色非常非常深，几乎是黑色的。
It's actually my favorite kind of bread.
它其实是我最喜欢的一种面包。
So, what does it taste like or what's the difference between whole wheat bread and rye
那么，它尝起来是什么味道，或者全麦面包和黑麦面包有什么区别？
bread?
面包？
Rye bread is much heavier.
黑麦面包要重得多。
It has a stronger flavor.
它的味道更浓。
Whole wheat bread is lighter.
全麦面包更轻一些。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So, obviously, it may be a little bit difficult to understand the differences between the
所以，显然，理解这些面包之间的区别可能有点困难，
breads, but we'll post pictures on the site so you can see them.
但我们会在网站上贴出图片，这样你们就能看到了。
And also, well, you have to go out to the bakery and try them so you can taste the difference.
而且，嗯，你们还得去面包店亲自尝尝，才能尝出区别。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So, now let's move on to language takeaway part two and talk about a little bit more
那么，现在我们进入语言要点第二部分，再谈谈
of the other vocab found in this lesson.
这节课中出现的其他词汇。
Welcome to Al's Bakery.
欢迎来到阿尔的面包店。
What can I get you?
您想要点什么？
Hi.
你好。
Let me get a dozen croissants, four blueberry muffins, and a loaf of sourdough bread.
我要一打牛角包、四个蓝莓松饼和一条酸面包。
Sure.
好的。
Would you like to have the loaf sliced?
需要把面包切片吗？
No, that's okay.
不用了，就这样吧。
Do you have any whole wheat bread?
你们有全麦面包吗？
Oh, we're out at the moment.
哦，现在卖完了。
May I suggest some rye bread?
我可以推荐一些黑麦面包吗？
Sure.
好的。
That sounds good.
听起来不错。
Do you have any cakes?
你们有蛋糕吗？
We have various birthday cakes and also some ice cream cakes.
我们有各种生日蛋糕，还有一些冰淇淋蛋糕。
I'll just take a cheesecake.
我就拿一个芝士蛋糕吧。
Will that be all?
就这些了吗？
Yes.
是的。
Your total is $43.20.
总共是43.20美元。
So, when you want to go buy some bread or some baked goods, you have to know how to
所以，当你想去买面包或烘焙食品时，你得知道怎么
count those goods.
数这些东西。
Okay, so today we have a couple of words to help you count bread.
好的，今天我们有几个词来帮你数面包。
The first one we have is dozen.
第一个词是“一打”。
That's right.
没错。
So, for croissants, as you can see, it's a countable noun.
所以，对于牛角包，如你所见，它是一个可数名词。
And so, when you ask for a dozen croissants, you're asking for 12.
当你点一打牛角包时，你是在要12个。
That's right.
没错。
So, in English, the word dozen means 12.
所以，在英语中，“一打”这个词意思是12。
You can buy a dozen eggs or in this case, a dozen blueberry muffins maybe.
你可以买一打鸡蛋，或者在这种情况下，一打蓝莓松饼。
Okay.
好的。
So, it's a very popular term, a dozen or a half a dozen.
所以，这是一个很常用的词，“一打”或“半打”。
Sometimes people just buy six.
有时候人们只买六个。
That's right.
没错。
So, half a dozen is six.
所以，“半打”就是六个。
A whole dozen, just say dozen, is 12.
一整打，直接说“一打”，就是12个。
You can also have something special called a baker's dozen.
你还可以有一样特别的东西，叫“面包师的一打”。
Yes, I've heard about this.
是的，我听说过这个。
What is a baker's dozen?
什么是“面包师的一打”？
Well, a baker's dozen is basically a present the baker gives you.
嗯，“面包师的一打”基本上就是面包师送你的礼物。
So, you buy 12, maybe 12 croissants and the baker gives you one more.
所以，你买12个，比如12个牛角包，面包师会多给你一个。
Wow, so you get 13.
哇，所以你得到13个。
Yes.
是的。
A baker's dozen is 13.
“面包师的一打”就是13个。
But do you ask for a baker's dozen or does the baker say, I'm going to give you the baker's
但你是主动要“面包师的一打”，还是面包师会说，“我给你面包师的
dozen?
一打”？
I don't think I've ever asked for it.
我想我从来没主动要过。
I think when I've bought bagels and I say I want a dozen bagels, they give me a baker's
我想当我买百吉饼时，我说我要一打百吉饼，他们就会给我“面包师的
dozen.
一打”。
They give me 13.
他们给我13个。
Okay.
好的。
So, when you're buying bread, now obviously you don't really buy a dozen sourdough breads.
所以，当你买面包时，显然你不会真的买一打酸面包。
You buy a dozen loaves of sourdough bread.
你会买一打条酸面包。
So, the countable noun here is a loaf of bread.
所以，这里的可数名词是“一条面包”。
One loaf, two loaves.
一条，两条。
Now, this is very interesting because in English, we don't have that many counting words, measure
这很有意思，因为在英语里，我们没有那么多量词或计量词。
words.
词。
Right.
对。
But for bread, we do actually have this special word.
但对于面包，我们确实有这么一个特别的词。
So, you can say, I would like two loaves of sourdough bread.
所以你可以说：我想要两条酸面包。
Okay.
好的。
And a loaf or loaves in the plural, what is it exactly?
那“a loaf”或者复数“loaves”到底是什么呢？
It's one big piece.
就是一大块。
So, for example, you have maybe one little piece of bread.
比如，你可能有一小块面包。
It's called a slice.
那叫一片。
That's what you eat.
那是你吃的东西。
But when you buy the bread, you have many, many, many slices together.
但当你买面包时，你会有很多很多片叠在一起。
Before you cut the bread, that's called a loaf.
在切面包之前，那叫一条。
Very good.
非常好。
And this is the reason why the baker or the person attending the shop asked if he would
这就是为什么面包师或店员会问他要不要
like to have the loaf sliced.
把面包切片。
Would you like the loaf sliced?
您想要把面包切片吗？
That means, would you like us to cut pieces of bread from this loaf?
意思是：您要我们把面包切成片吗？
Because sliced bread is how you eat it.
因为切片面包才是你吃的方式。
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
You don't really take a whole loaf of bread and start eating it like that.
你不会真的拿一整条面包直接那样啃。
Like an animal.
像动物一样。
No.
不。
You cut it into slices.
你会把它切成片。
So, sliced bread, we say, is one option.
所以切片面包，我们说，是一种选择。
You can also have unsliced, which means when you go home, you cut it yourself.
你也可以选不切片的，意思是回家后自己切。
So this is a very particular word as well because you have the adjective to have sliced
这也是一个很特别的词，因为你有形容词“sliced”
bread.
面包。
You also have the verb to slice the bread.
你还有动词“to slice”面包。
That means to cut it into slices.
意思是把它切成片。
And of course, you have the noun slices of bread.
当然，你还有名词“slices of bread”。
So you have the individual pieces.
就是那些单独的小块。
So it can be a verb, an adjective, and a noun.
所以它可以是动词、形容词和名词。
That's right.
没错。
It can be a little confusing, but I recommend you all check out the website and practice
这可能有点让人困惑，但我建议你们都去网站看看，并在评论区
a little bit in the comments section.
练习一下。
All right.
好的。
Good.
好。
So let's take a listen to the dialogue one last time.
那我们最后再听一遍对话。
Welcome to Al's Bakery.
欢迎来到阿尔面包店。
What can I get you?
您要点什么？
Hi.
你好。
Let me get a dozen croissants, four blueberry muffins, and a loaf of sourdough bread.
我要一打牛角包、四个蓝莓马芬和一条酸面包。
Sure.
好的。
Would you like to have the loaf sliced?
您想要把面包切片吗？
No, that's okay.
不用了，没关系。
Do you have any whole wheat bread?
你们有全麦面包吗？
Oh, we're out at the moment.
哦，现在卖完了。
May I suggest some rye bread?
我可以推荐一些黑麦面包吗？
Sure.
好的。
That sounds good.
听起来不错。
Do you have any cakes?
你们有蛋糕吗？
We have various birthday cakes and also some ice cream cakes.
我们有各种生日蛋糕，还有一些冰淇淋蛋糕。
I'll just take a cheesecake.
我就拿一个芝士蛋糕吧。
Will that be all?
就这些吗？
Yes.
是的。
Your total is $43.20.
您总共是43.20美元。
All right.
好的。
So speaking about breads now, there is some particular ingredients that we don't mention
说到面包，对话里显然没有提到一些特别的
in the dialogue, obviously.
配料。
But they're worth mentioning, what is the one main characteristic that most breads have?
但它们值得一提，大多数面包的一个主要特点是什么？
Yeast.
酵母。
That's right.
没错。
Y-E-A-S-T.
Y-E-A-S-T。
Yeast.
酵母。
And yeast is actually alive.
酵母实际上是活的。
It's an animal.
它是一种动物。
It's like a bacteria.
像一种细菌。
That's right.
没错。
And so you wonder why are some breads flat and why are some breads big, poofy, large?
所以你会想，为什么有些面包是扁的，有些面包是大的、蓬松的、大的？
Well, yeast is why.
嗯，酵母就是原因。
Basically, you can't have a big poofy bread, a big, large, tall bread, unless you have
基本上，你不可能有大的蓬松面包、大的、高的面包，除非你有
this yeast.
这种酵母。
So yeast is what makes the bread rise.
所以酵母是让面包发酵的东西。
Yes.
是的。
And we also mentioned flour, which is basically just a powder made out of some type of grain
我们还提到了面粉，它基本上是一种粉末，通常由某种谷物
usually.
制成。
Yeah.
嗯。
Usually it's made out of wheat.
通常它是用小麦做的。
Obviously, whole wheat is a little bit different from the white flour, which would be a different
显然，全麦面粉和普通白面粉有点不同，后者是另一种
processed wheat.
加工过的小麦。
But we also have different things that you can even have rice flour.
但我们还有不同的东西，你甚至可以用米粉。
Right.
没错。
Corn flour.
玉米粉。
So corn bread would be, of course, yellow because corn is yellow.
所以玉米面包当然是黄色的，因为玉米是黄色的。
Now, so you can hear that we say the word flour like a rose is a flower, but it's actually
现在，你可以听到我们说“flour”这个词，就像玫瑰是“flower”，但实际上
spelled different.
拼写不同。
F-L-O-U-R, flour.
F-L-O-U-R，flour。
So there's two different things.
所以这是两个不同的东西。
There's flours in your garden and there's flour, F-L-O-U-R, which is something you can
花园里有花（flowers），还有面粉（flour），F-L-O-U-R，这是你可以
cook with.
用来烹饪的东西。
That's right.
没错。
These are called homophones.
这些叫做同音异义词。
So they basically have the same pronunciation, but very different spellings.
所以它们基本上发音相同，但拼写非常不同。
And very different meanings.
而且意思也完全不同。
Exactly.
正是。
So a very interesting lesson for us today.
所以今天对我们来说是一堂非常有趣的课。
Go out, get some bread, try some of these if you have them available.
出去买些面包，如果有的话，试试这些种类。
But also, come to the questions and comments section and tell us about maybe your local
但也要来问答区，告诉我们你当地的
bread.
面包。
I know that many countries around the world have very specific types of bread.
我知道世界上很多国家都有非常特定的面包种类。
That's right.
没错。
Write some names down for us, send us your pictures, and we'll see you on the website.
给我们写下一些名字，发来你的照片，我们网站上见。
All right.
好的。
Bye, guys.
再见，各位。
That way we don't have to worry about typing out the whole disclaimer and come up with
这样我们就不用担心最后打出整个免责声明并想出
all the answers at the end.
所有答案了。
And we just love hearing from you.
我们就是喜欢收到你们的消息。
That's right.
没错。
Thank you so much.
非常感谢。
Oh, God.
哦，天哪。
Oh, I saw that one.
哦，我看到了那个。
That's good.
那不错。
I'm not going to watch that.
我不打算看那个。